A Guide to the Gertrude E. Perlmann papers, Rockefeller University Faculty FA189
Rockefeller Archive Center
- Glass slides, 122 items
  - Glass slides: Plates of experimental work 2 x 10 glass plates include (Box 68)
    - Experiment 431 Pepsin w/calculations, 3 items
    - Experiment 432 Pepsin, 3 items
    - Experiment 566 Pepsin Urea ", 3 items
    - Experiment 926 Pepsin-phosphodesterase treated, 2 items
      Includes (1) 2 x 6, (1) 2 x 4.
    - Experiment 927 Pepsin-control, 2 items
    - Experiment 1014 Urea Pepsin w/calculations, 2 items
    - Experiment 1015 Urea, 2 items
    - Experiment 1023 Urea treated Pepsin-electrophoretic sub fraction, 3 items
  - 2 x 10 glass plates boxed Sept. 13 [Year?] - Sedimentation equilibrium on pepsinogen in 10% ethanol, 0% ethanol, 7 items (Box 68)
  - 2 x 2 lantern slides boxed, 10 items (Box 68)
  - 2 x 2 lantern slides boxed. No slide identification, 50 items (Box 68)
  - 3 x 4 glass slides, 2 wooden cases
    Charts, graphs, readings of laboratory results. Used in publications and talks. Slide identification on Inside case cover.
    - Case #1 - Slides 1-50 (Box 69)
    - Case #2 - Slides 1-50 (Box 70)
      Lacks 2, 19, 49, 50.
  - 2 x 2 lantern slides, 63 items (Box 71)
    Charts, tables, graphs of laboratory results. Used in publications and talks.
    Includes: Black leather case. Slide identification on inside case cover. Some slides missing and not all identified.
  - 3 metal cases containing 2 x 2 lantern slides, 3 metal cases
    - 2 x 2 lantern slides, 91 items (Box 72)
      Slide identification on inside case cover. Some slides missing and not all identified.
    - 2 x 2 lantern slides, 37 items (Box 73)
    - 2 x 2 lantern slides, 77 items (Box 74)
      No slide identification.
  - 4 x 5 glass slides, 2 metal cases, 2 drawers each (Box 76, Box 75)
    Electrophoretic and refraction examinations of biological compounds for Perlmann laboratory work and other laboratories including: Drs. Lancefield, Goebel, Kunitz, Genest, Horsfall, Trager and Tamm.
  - Drawings of tables, graphs, illustrations (Package 1)
    Slides and photographs used in lectures or publications made from these drawings.
  - Framed 3 dimensional photographs of protein molecules, 2 items (Package 1)
- Administrative correspondence and employment record, 1945-1974; 1 box (2½ inches) (Box 77)
  Complete employment record of Dr. Perlmann, curriculum vitae, photographs and administrative correspondence. The correspondence deals with laboratory changes; changes in organization, travel abroad and promotion to Professor.
  Immediate Source of Acquisition note
  This group of papers was deposited at the Archives, by the Office of Faculty and Student Records. Received or inventoried: June 1980.
  - 1945-1960 (Folder 1)
  - 1961-1974 (Folder 2)
    Bibliography
    PapersVan Slyke, D.D. Note on portable form of the manometric gas apparatus, and on certain points in the technique of its use. J Biol Chem 73: 121 (1927).Van Slyke, D.D. and Sendroy, J., Jr. Carbon dioxide factors for the manometric blood gas apparatus. J Biol Chem 73: 127 (1927).Van Slyke, D.D. Determination of urea by gasometric measurement of the carbon dioxide formed by the action of urease. J Biol Chem 73: 695 (1927).Hiller, A., McIntosh, J.F. and Van Slyke, D.D. The excretion of albumin and globulin in nephritis. J Clin Invest 4: 235 (1927).Van Slyke, D.D. Certain aspects of the physical chemistry of the blood. Pasteur Lecture. Proc Inst Med Chicago 6: 173 (1927).Van Slyke, D.D., Hiller, A. and Knud Berthelsen. A gasometric micromethod for determination of iodates and sulfates, and its application to the estimation of total base in blood serum. J Biol Chem 74: 659 (1927).Van Slyke, D.D. and Hiller, A. Gasometric determination of hemoglobin by the carbon monoxide capacity method. J Biol Chem 78: 807 (1928).Van Slyke, D.D., Sendroy, J., Jr., Hastings, A.B. and Neill, J.M. Studies of gas and electrolyte equilibria in blood. X. The solubility of carbon dioxide at 38° in water, salt solution, serum, and blood cells; J Biol Chem 78: 765 (1928).Van Slyke, D.D. and Sendroy, J., Jr. Studies of gas and electrolyte equilibria in blood. XI. The solubility of hydrogen at 38° in blood serum and cells. J Biol Chem 78: 801 (1928).Hastings, A.B., Sendroy, J., Jr. and Van Slyke, D.D. Studies of gas and electrolyte equilibria in blood. XII. The value of pK in the Henderson-Hasselbalch equation for blood serum. J Biol Chem 79: 183 (1928).Hastings, A.B., Sendroy, J., Jr., McIntosh, J.F. and Van Slyke, D.D. Studies of gas and electrolyte equilibria in blood. XIII. The distribution of chloride and bicarbonate in the blood of normal and pathological human subjects. J Biol Chem 79: 193 (1928).Van Slyke, D.D., Hastings, A.B., Hiller, A. and Sendroy, J., Jr. Studies of gas and electrolyte equilibria in blood. XIV. The amounts of alkali bound by serum albumin and globulin. J Biol Chem 79: 769 (1928).Van Slyke, D.D. and Sendroy, J., Jr. Studies of gas and electrolyte equilibria in blood. XV. Line charts for graphic calculations by the Henderson-Hasselbalch equation, and for calculating plasma carbon dioxide content from whole blood content. J Biol Chem 79: 731 (1928).Van Slyke, D.D. and Hawkins, J.A. A gasometric method for determination of reducing sugars, and its application to analysis of blood and urine. J Biol Chem 79: 739 (1928).Christie, R.V., Sendroy, J., Jr. and Van Slyke, D.D. The distribution of electrolytes in haemophilic blood. Quart J Med 22: 65 (1928).Møller, E., McIntosh, J.F. and Van Slyke, D.D. Studies of urea excretion. II. Relationship between urine volume and the rate of urea excretion by normal adults. J Clin Invest 6: 427 (1928).Mcintosh, J.F., Møller, E. and Van Slyke, D.D. Studies of urea excretion. III. The influence of body size on urea output. J Clin Invest 6: 467 (1928).Møller, E., McIntosh, J.E. and Van Slyke, D.D. Studies of urea excretion. IV. Relationship between urine volume and rate of urea excretion by patients with Bright's disease. J Clin Invest 6: 485 (1928).Hawkins, J.A. and Van Slyke, D.D. A time method for determination of reducing sugars, and its application to analysis of blood and urine. J Biol Chem 81: 459 (1929).Van Slyke, D.D. Discussion. The 1928 Silliman Lectures. Science 69: 163 (1929).Van Slyke, D.D. and Hawkins, J. Gasometric determination of fermentable sugar in blood and urine. J Biol Chem 83: 51 (1929).Van Slyke, D.D. Determination of acetone bodies in blood and urine. J Biol Chem 83: 415 (1929).Van Slyke, D.D. Manometric determination of primary amino nitrogen and its application to blood analysis. J Biol Chem 83: 425 (1929).Van Slyke, D.D. Manometric determination of urea in blood and urine by the hypobromite reaction. J Biol Chem 83: 449 (1929).Van Slyke, D.D. and Hiller, A. Gasometric determination of methemoglobin. J Biol Chem 84: 205 (1929).Van Slyke, D.D. and Hiller, A. Gasometric control of standard solutions for the Palmer hemoglobin method. J Biol Chem 84: 211 (1929).Van Slyke, D.D. and Sendroy, J., Jr. Gasometric determination of oxalic acid and calcium, and its application to serum analysis. J Biol Chem 84: 217 (1929).Hawkins, J.A. and Van Slyke, D.D. Comparison of rates of sugar disappearance and carbon dioxide formation during fermentation of glucose. J Biol Chem 84: 243 (1929).Hawkins, J.A., MacKay., B. and Van Slyke, D.D. Glucose excretion in Bright's disease. J Clin Invest 8: 107 (1929).Sendroy, J., Jr., Liu, S.H. and Van Slyke, D.D. The gasometric estimation of the relative affinity constant for carbon monoxide and oxygen in whole blood at 38°. Amer J Physiol 90: 511 (1929).Van Slyke, D.D. Gasometrische Mikro-Kjeldahl-Stickstoffbestimmung. Abderhalden Handbuch der biologischen Arbeitmethoden Abt. IV Teil 13: 21 (1930).Van Slyke, D.D. Bestimmung von Harnstoff durch gasometrische Messung des durch die Einwirkung von Urease gebildeten Kohlendioxydes.Abderhalden Handbuch der biologlschen Arbeitsmethoden Abt. IV Teil 1 749 (1930).Moore, N.S. and Van Slyke, D.D. The relationships between plasma specific gravity, plasma protein content and edema in nephritis. J Clin Invest 8: 337 (1930).Van Slyke, D.D., McIntosh, J.F., Møller, E., Hannon, R.R. and Johnston, C. Studies of urea excretion. VI. Comparison of the blood urea clearance with certain other measures of renal function. J Clin Invest 8: 357 (1930).Sendroy, J., Jr., Liu, S.H. and Van Slyke, D.D. Estimation gazometrique de la constante d'affinite relative pour l'oxyge de carbone et l'oxygene dans le sang total a 38°. Bull Soc Chim Biol 13: 532 (1930).Van Slyke, D.D. and Hawkins, J.A. Studies of gas and electrolyte equilibria in blood. XVI. The evolution of carbon dioxide from blood and buffer solutions. J Biol Chem 87: 265 (1930).Van Slyke, D.D., Stillman, E., Møller, E., Ehrich, W., McIntosh, J.F., Leiter, L., MacKay, E.M., Hannon, R.R., Moore, N.S. and Johnson, C. Observations on the courses of different types of Bright's disease, and on the resultant changes in renal anatomy. Medicine 9: 257 (1930).Rhoads, CP., Van Slyke, D.D., Hiller, A. and Alving, A. Studies of renal metabolism. Proc Soc Exp Biol Med 28: 776 (1931); Trans Assn Amer Physicians 46: 301 (1931).Sendroy, J., Jr., Hiller, A. and Van Slyke, D.D. Determination of lung volume by respiration of oxygen without forced breathing. J Exp Med 55: 361 (1932).Van Slyke, D.D. and Sendroy, J., Jr. Manometric analysis of gas mixtures. I. The determination, by simple absorption, of carbon dioxide, oxygen and nitrogen in mixtures of these gases. J Biol Chem 95: 509 (1932).Van Slyke, D.D., Sendroy, J., Jr. and Liu, S.H. Manometric analysis of gas mixtures. II. Carbon dioxide by the isolation method. J Biol Chem 95: 531 (1932).Van Slyke, D.D., Sendroy, J., Jr. and Liu, S.H. Manometric analysis of gas mixtures. III, Manometric determination of carbon dioxide tension and pH of blood. J Biol Chem 95: 547 (1932).Van Slyke, D.D. and Hanke, M.E. Manometric, analysis of gas mixtures. IV. Hydrogen and oxygen by combustion. J Biol Chem 95: 569 (1932).Van Slyke, D.D. and Hanke, M.E. Manometric analysis of gas mixtures. V. Hydrogen by absorption with Paal's picrate-pallidium solution. J Biol Chem 95: 587 (1932).Van Slyke, D.D. and Cope, C.L. Simplified colorimetric determination of blood urea clearance. Proc Soc Exp Biol Med 29: 1169 (1932).Van Slyke, D.D., Alving, A. and Rose, W.C. Studies of urea excretion. VII. The effects of posture and exercise on urea excretion. J Clin Invest 11: 1053 (1932).Page, I.H. and Van Slyke, D.D. A simple test for plasma protein contents below the edema-producing level. JAMA 99: 1344 (1932).Van Slyke, D.D. and Kugel, V.H. Use of Somogyi's filtrate to increase the specificity of the gasometric blood sugar method. J Biol Chem 102: 51 (1933).Van Slyke, D.D., Dillon, R.T. and Hiller, A. Crystallization of a compound of hemoglobin and carbon dioxide. Proc Nat Acad Sci 19: 828 (1933).Van Slyke, D.D. and Kugel, V.H. Improvements in manometric micro-Kjeldahl and blood urea methods. J Biol Chem 102: 489 (1933).Van Slyke, D.D. and Hiller, A. Determination of ammonia in blood. J Biol Chem 102: 499 (1933).Van Slyke, D.D. and Sendroy, J., Jr. Studies of gas and electrolyte equilibria in blood. XVII. The effect of oxygenation and reduction on the carbon dioxide absorption curve and the pK' of whole blood. J Biol Chem 102: 505 (1933).Van Slyke, D.D., Page, I.H. and Kirk, E. A manometric micro method for determination of carbon in organic compounds. J Biol Chem 102: 635 (1933).Van Slyke, D.D. and Kirk, E. Comparison of gasometric, colorimetric, and titrimetric determinations of amino nitrogen in blood and urine. J Biol Chem 102: 651 (1933).Peters, J.P. and Van Slyke, D.D. Analysen von Gasgemischen. Handbuch der biol Arbeits Abt. 5 Teil 10 113 (1934).Peters, J.P. and Van Slyke, D.D. Gasometrische Methoden zur Analyse von Blut und anderen Losungen. Handbuch der biol Arbeits Abt. 5 Teil 10 203 (1934).Van Slyke, D.D. Acidosis and alkalosis. Bull NY Acad Med 10: 103 (1934).Van Slyke, D.D. Tests of renal function in Bright's disease. Med Clin N Amer 17: 1179 (1934).Van Slyke, D.D., Dillon, R.T. and Margaria, R. Studies of gas and electrolyte equilibria in blood. XVIII. Solubility and physical state of atmospheric nitrogen in blood cells and plasma. J Biol Chem 105: 571 (1934).Sendroy, J., Jr., Dillon, R.T. and Van Slyke, D.D. Studies of gas and electrolyte equilibria in blood. XIX. Solubility and physical state of uncombined oxygen in blood. J Biol Chem 105: 597 (1934).Rhoads, C.P., Alving, A.S., Hiller, A. and Van Slyke, D.D. The functional effect of explanting one kidney and removing the other. Amer J Physiol 109: 329 (1934).Van Slyke, D.D., Rhoads, CP., Hiller, A. and Alving, A.S. Relationships between urea excretion, renal blood flow, renal oxygen consumption and diuresis. The mechanism of urea excretion. Amer J Physiol 109: 336 (1934).Kirk, E., Page, I.H. and Van Slyke, D.D. Gasometric microdetermination of lipids in plasma, blood cells, and tissues. J Biol Chem 106: 203 (1934).Sendroy, J., Jr., Scelig, S. and Van Slyko, D.D. Studies of acidosis. XXII. Application of the Henderson-Hasselbalch equation to human urine. J Biol Chem 106: 463 (1934).Sendroy, J., Jr., Seelig, S. and Van Slyke, D.D. Studies of acidosis. XXIII. The carbon dioxide tension and acid-base balance of human urine. J Biol Chem 106: 479 (1934).Alving, A.S. and Van Slyke, D.D. The significance of concentration and dilution tests in Bright's disease. J Clin Invest 13: 969 (1934).Van Slyke, D.D., Rhoads, CP., Hiller, A. and Alving, A.S. The relationship of the urea clearance to the renal blood flow. Amfr J Physiol 110: 387 (1934).Rhoads, CP., Van Slyke, D.D., Hiller, A. and Alving, A.S. The effects of novocainization and total section of the nerves of the renal pedicle on renal blood and function. Amer J Physiol 110: 392 (1934).Van Slyke, D.D., Page, I.H., Kirk, E. and Farr, L.E. Nature of nitrogenous constituents in petroleum ether extract of plasma. Proc Soc Exp Biol Med 32: 837 (1935).Van Slyke, D.D., Page, I.H., Hiller, A. and Kirk, E. Studies of urea excretion. IX. Comparison of urea clearances calculated from the excretion of urea, of urea plus ammonia, and of nitrogen determinable by hypobromite. J Clin Invest 14: 901 (1935).Van Slyke, D.D., Hiller, A. and Miller, B.F. The clearance, extraction percentage and estimated filtration of sodium ferrocyanide in the mammalian kidney. Comparison with inulin, creatinine and urea. Amer J Physiol 113: 611 (1935).Van Slyke, D.D., Hiller, A. and Miller, B.F. The distribution of ferrocyanide, inulin, creatinine and urea in the blood and its effect on the significance of their extraction percentages. Amer J Physiol 113: 629 (1935).Page, I.H., Kirk, E., Lewis, W.H., Jr., Thompson, W.R. and Van Slyke, D.D. Plasm
- Collected papers, (volume)